<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Journal du Fort Kamanaitiquoya a la Rivière de Montreal, 1804.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="Malhiot, François Victoire.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">Malhiot, François Victoire. Journal du Fort Kamanaitiquoya a la Rivière de Montreal, 1804. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0014</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0014</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2357.1</span></p>







<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This journal by François-Victoire Malhiot, a clerk for the North West Company, is an anecdotal narrative of the events which occurred at Lac du Flambeau between 9 July 1804 and 15 June 1805.  Malhiot discusses his health problems, the fur trade with the local Ojibway peoples, the starvation suffered by the traders and Natives due to the scarcity of food, the region's climate, and the tense and often hostile relations between Natives and traders. Malhiot further provides an inventory of the pelts obtained from the Ojibways and brings attention to the numerous complaints expressed by the voyageurs in regards to their working conditions.  Finally, taking great pride in being an employee for the North West Company, Malhiot details the construction of the fort at Lac du Flambeau. </p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ce document constitue le journal de bord de François-Victoire Malhiot, commis pour la Compagnie du Nord Ouest. On y trouve des anecdotes et des événements survenus au Lac du Flambeau entre le 9 juillet 1804 et le 15 juin 1805. Il y est notamment question de ses problèmes de santé, des échanges commerciaux avec les Ojibways de la région, des nombreuses famines et disettes, du climat, et de tensions et conflits entre autochtones et traiteurs. Malhiot y dresse aussi des inventaires des pelleteries obtenues des Amérindiens. L'auteur discute enfin des nombreuses plaintes des voyageurs à l'égard de leurs conditions de travail et décrit la construction du fort du Lac du Flambeau, que le rend très fier de travailler pour la compagnie.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
