<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>The Indians from Fort William to Lake of the Woods, ca. 1806.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="McLoughlin, John.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">McLoughlin, John. The Indians from Fort William to Lake of the Woods, ca. 1806. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0023</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0023</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2364</span></p>






<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>Written by John McLoughlin during his travels from Fort William to Lake of the Woods, this manuscript contains descriptions of the topography, flora, fauna, mineral resources, climate and numerous waterways of the region. The author also describes the lifestyle of the local Ojibway, detailing their religious beliefs, political institutions, marital and burial customs, and kinship system.  While McLoughlin is impressed by the Ojibway&#8217;s spirit of individuality, generosity, and equality, he nonetheless views them as ignorant and superstitious. He writes also of their subsistence, largely based on hunting game and gathering wild rice, and of their complex relationship with the North West Company. This text is not dated but was revised on 18 May 1840.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ce texte fut écrit par John McLoughlin lors de ses voyages du Fort William jusqu'à Lake of the Woods. L'auteur y décrit la topographie du pays, sa faune, sa flore, ses ressources minières, son climat et ses nombreux cours d'eau. Il fournit aussi une description détaillée du mode de vie des Ojibways de cet endroit. Il est étonné par leur esprit d'individualité, de générosité et d'égalité, tout en les trouvant ignorants et superstitieux. Il décrit leurs croyances religieuses, institutions politiques, coutumes de mariage et de deuil, et système de parenté. Il parle aussi de leur mode de subsistance, basé sur la chasse ainsi que la cueillette de riz sauvage, et de leur rapport complexe avec la Compagnie du Nord Ouest. Ce texte est non daté, mais il fut revisé le 18 mai 1840.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
