<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Men's Names at the Athabasca River Department etc., 1805.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="North West Company.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">North West Company. Men's Names at the Athabasca River Department <span class="AddHand-editors">[etc.]</span>, 1805. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0031</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0031</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2370.3</span></p>






<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This document contains tables indicating the names of every person employed by the North West Company for the year 1805 in the following areas: Athabasca, Upper Fort des Prairies, Lower Fort des Prairies, English River, Upper Red River, Lower Red River, Fort Dauphin, Rat River, Lake Winnipeg, Lake Nipigon, Red Lake/Lac Seul, Pic, Fond du Lac, Rivière des Saulteux, Lac la Pluie, Lac du Flambeau, Point Chagouamigon, and Kamanistiquia.  These tables specify the name, position (clerk, interpreter, guide, foreman, steersman, middleman, summer voyageur), amount of years left to serve, and the annual wage of each individual.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ce document constitue un ensemble de tableaux indiquant les noms de tous les employés de la Compagnie du Nord Ouest pour l'année 1805, et ce, dans les départements suivants: Athabasca; Upper Fort des Prairies; Lower Fort des Prairies; English River; Upper Red River; Lower Red River; Fort Dauphin; Rat River; Lac Winnipeg; Lac Nipigon; Red Lake/Lac Seul; Pic; Fond du Lac; Rivière des Saulteux; Lac la Pluie; Lac du Flambeau; Point Chagouamigon; Kamanistiquia. Les tableaux indiquent le nom, la position (commis, interprète, guide, avant, gouvernail, milieu, voyageur d'été), le salaire annuel de chaque individu et le nombre d'années leur restant à servir.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
