<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Travels in the Red River Department (Abridged), 1806.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="Henry, Alexander.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">Henry, Alexander. Travels in the Red River Department (Abridged), 1806. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0024</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0024</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2365</span></p>










<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This document is an account of the travels of Alexander Henry (the younger) along the Missouri River, amongst the Mandan peoples, during the summer of 1806. Henry describes the Mandans' marriage and burial customs, as well as their trade and warfare activities. Henry also discusses his travels in the regions of several other Native groups, including the nearby Gros Ventres (Hidatsa).  Along with descriptions of their military, social, political and economic institutions, Henry also depicts the Gros Ventres as a spiritual people who venerate the white buffalo.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ce récit de voyage fut écrit par Alexander Henry (le jeune) au cours de l'été 1806, alors qu'il se rendit au pays des Mandans, le long du fleuve Missouri. Henry présente des descriptions détaillées de leurs pratiques funéraires, coutumes de mariage, ainsi que de leurs activités économiques et guerrières. Henry décrit aussi le mode de vie des Gros Ventres (Hidatsa) qui, selon lui, vénèrent le bison blanc. Il y est aussi question des institutions militaires, sociales, politiques et économiques des Gros Ventres.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
