<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Journal Kept at Slave Lake, 1802.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="Wentzel, Willard Ferdinand.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">Wentzel, Willard Ferdinand. Journal Kept at Slave Lake, 1802. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0013</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0013</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2356a</span></p>







<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This journal, which accompanies the letters found in document 2356, was kept by Willard F. Wentzel, a clerk for the North West Company, at Slave Lake during the summer of 1802.  Wentzel reports on the voyageurs' hunting activities, the relationships and trade developing between the voyageurs and Natives, and the building of a new trading post.  The author also discusses the negative effects of competing with the XY Company, as well as his own tense relations with some local Natives. Wentzel further mentions the publication of Sir Alexander Mackenzie's <span class="titleCited">Journal </span>and the latter&#8217;s knighting by the King of England in 1801.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ce journal, qui accompagne les lettres trouvées en 2356, fut tenu par Willard F. Wentzel, un commis au service de la Compagnie du Nord Ouest au Lac des Esclaves durant l'été de 1802. Wentzel y rapporte notamment les activités de chasse des voyageurs, leurs rapports et échanges commerciaux avec les autochtones de la région, ainsi que la construction d'un poste de traite. L'auteur discute des effets néfastes de la compétition avec la Compagnie XY et des relations tendues entre lui et certaines autochtones de la région. Wentzel mentionne aussi la publication du Journal de Sir Alexander Mackenzie et que ce dernier a été fait Chevalier par la roi d'Angleterre en 1801.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
