<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Fifteen letters from Wentzel at Mackenzie River to Roderick Mackenzie, 1807-1824.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="Wentzel, Willard Ferdinand.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">Wentzel, Willard Ferdinand. Fifteen letters from Wentzel at Mackenzie River to Roderick Mackenzie, 1807-1824. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0012</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0012</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2356</span></p>






















<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This document consists of fifteen letters written by Willard F. Wentzel to Roderick Mackenzie between 27 March 1807 and 1 March 1824. Wentzel, a North West Company clerk in the Slave Lake and Horn Mountain area, describes the region's topography, waterways, minerals, flora, fauna and climate. He also discusses the lifestyle of the Beaver peoples and includes an extensive portrait (tainted with extreme prejudice for certain customs) of their culture and institutions.  These letters contain an English-Beaver dictionary, details on the history and state of the fur trade in the Athabasca region, and descriptions of the North West Company&#8217;s rivalry with the Hudson's Bay and XY companies. Wentzel writes of starvation, epidemics, cold weather, and severe tensions with nearby Natives. He also reports on the death of B. Frobisher near Moose Lake Fort due to exhaustion and the cold (see document 2361). Finally, Wentzel writes about the Franklin expedition to the Coppermine River region, of which he participated in for a short while.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ces 15 lettres furent écrites par Willard F. Wentzel entre le 27 mars 1807 et le 1er mars 1824. Elles sont adressées à Roderick Mackenzie. Wentzel, un commis de  la Compagnie du Nord Ouest posté dans la région du Lac des Esclaves et de Horn Mountain, décrit la topographie, les cours d'eaux, les minéraux, la flore, la faune et le climat de cette région. Il explique le mode de vie des Indiens Beaver et offre un portrait détaillé de leurs croyances et institutions, tout en exprimant ses préjugés sur quelques coutumes. Il fournit un dictionnaire anglais-beaver et discute de l'histoire et de l'état du commerce des fourrures dans l'Athabasca, marqué par la rivalité de la Compagnie du Nord Ouest avec la Compagnie de la Baie d'Hudson et la Compagnie XY. Il parle de famines, d'épidémies et de tensions sévères avec les Indiens. Il mentionne aussi que B. Frobisher est décédé d'épuisement et de froid non loin de Moose Lake Fort (voir document 2361). Enfin, Wentzel mentionne l'expédition de Franklin dans la région de la rivière Coppermine, expédition à laquelle il prit part pour quelque temps.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
