<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Some Account of the Department of Fond du Lac or Mississippi, 1807.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="Monk, George Henry.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">Monk, George Henry. Some Account of the Department of Fond du Lac or Mississippi, 1807. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0034</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0034</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2370.6</span></p>






<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>In this letter, dated 18 April 1807, North West Company clerk George H. Monk Jr. modestly replies to Roderick Mackenzie&#8217;s request that he produce a historical account of the Mississippi River region. Also included in this document is the journal Monk kept during his stay in the Fond du Lac area.  He describes the navigation from Fort William to the St-Louis River and details the several portages between these two strategic locations. He also reports on the arboreal flora, the local fauna and the various food resources found in the area such as wild rice, potatoes and maize. Further, he discusses the horticultural production of several North West Company posts located in the region.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Dans ce document daté du 18 avril 1807, le commis George H. Monk Jr. répond modestement à la requête de Roderick Mackenzie, qui lui a demandé de présenter une histoire particulière de la région du Mississippi. La deuxième partie du document est le journal de Monk, qui relate des événements survenus dans le département du Fond du Lac au cours de son séjour là-bas. Monk y brosse un tableau complet sur le déroulement d'un voyage entre Fort William et la rivière St-Louis, tout en décrivant les portages qui séparent ces endroits stratégiques. Il apporte des détails sur la flore arboricole et la faune ainsi que sur les ressources alimentaires de la région, telles que la riz sauvage, les patates et le maïs. Enfin, il décrit la production horticole de plusieurs postes de la Compagnie du Nord Ouest localisés dans la région.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
