<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Journal of the Fourth Expedition to the Missouri, 1806.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="McKenzie, Charles.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">McKenzie, Charles. Journal of the Fourth Expedition to the Missouri, 1806. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0011</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0011</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2355c</span></p>








<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This document is a journal Charles Mackenzie wrote in June 1806 during his voyage to Missouri to pursue trade with the Mandan Indians and their neighbours.  In it, Mackenzie discusses the recent Native warfare, the effects of disease on many Native groups and gives details on Native hunting activities, religious rituals and diplomacy.  He also relates an incident where, for trading purposes, he agrees to accompany some Cheyenne people back to their territory, which results in his discovery of new sources of beaver pelts. Mackenzie comments on the complex relationship between  &#8220;whites" and &#8220;Indians&#8221; and, despite finding opposition to his interest in the Missouri area, remains proud of being the first trader to return from this region with numerous pelts.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ce document constitue le journal de Charles Mackenzie, que ce dernier a écrit en juin 1806 lors de son voyage au Missouri afin d'y poursuivre la traite avec les Mandans et leurs voisins. L'auteur y discute de guerres récentes entre nations autochtones et note les effets dévastateurs de nombreuses épidémies. Il décrit des scènes de chasse au bison ainsi que des rituels religieux, et observe la diplomatie locale des Amérindiens. Il accepte d'accompagner des Cheyennes dans leur territoire, où il trouve de nouvelles sources de castor. Mackenzie décrit les relations complexes entre "blancs" et Indiens et, malgré le fait que certains partenaires ne voient pas l'importance de commercer au Missouri, il se dit fier d'être le premier traiteur à revenir de la région avec autant de pelleteries.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
