<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Letter to Judge Adam Mabane, 1787, with a copy of Jones's testimony 1783.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="Jones, John.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">Jones, John. Letter to Judge Adam Mabane, 1787, with a copy of Jones's testimony 1783. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0003</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0003</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2348.1-2</span></p>









<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This document is comprised of a letter, dated 10 November 1787, by John Jones to the Honourable Adam Mabane, Senior Judge of Court of Common Pleas for the District of Quebec.  Jones, a witness in the case of Jenkin Williams (Solicitor for General Haldimand) vs. Honourable John Cochrane, accuses Judge Mabane of preordaining a judgment with Mr. Williams before he allowed the defendant&#8217;s attorney, Mr. Panet, to present a defense testimony for his client Cochrane. He reproaches him for having deliberately misrepresented the facts and for failing to methodical keep records of the Court. Accompanying this letter is a copy of Mr. Jones' testimony and answers to the special interrogation put to him by Mr. Ogden, as well as a copy of the comments made by the judges.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Cette lettre datée du 10 novembre 1787 fut écrite par John Jones, témoin dans la cause qui opposa Jenkin Williams, solliciteur pour le Général Haldimand et l'Honorable John Cochrane, à l'Honorable Adam Mabane, alors juge senior de la Cour Civile du district de Québec. Jones accuse Mabane d'avoir prédéterminé un jugement, conjointement avec M. Williams, et ce, avant d'avoir entendu la défense de l'avocat Panet pour son client Cochrane. Il lui reproche ainsi d'avoir délibérément et faussement représenté les faits et d'avoir négligé de conserver avec méthode les documents de la Cour. Cette lettre est accompagnée d'une copie du témoignage de Jones en réponse à l'interrogatoire spécial ayant été déposé par M. Ogden, ainsi que d'une copie des commentaires des Juges.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
