<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Description of the Country around Lakes Superior and Huron, 1809.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="Johnston, John.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">Johnston, John. Description of the Country around Lakes Superior and Huron, 1809. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0018</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0018</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2360</span></p>







<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This document consists of a letter dated 21 September 1809 from John Johnston to Roderick Mackenzie describing Johnston&#8217;s travels in the Lake Superior region from 1792 to 1796 and in the winter of 1809. The author details the topography and geology of the region, with a special emphasis on landscapes, mineral resources, waterways as well as local trees, plants and wild flowers. He describes the quality of the soil, the local climate, and the various medicinal plants and roots used by local Indians. He writes about the capture of a beaver born with two tails and the finding of a well-preserved human head. Among his observations, Johnston comes to believe that the United States obtained lands which should have remained British as well as that the Earth is not flat at its poles.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ce document est une lettre de John Johnston à Roderick Mackenzie datée du 21 septembre 1809. L'auteur y discute de ses voyages dans le territoire du Lac Supérieur entre 1792 et 1796 et au cours de l'hiver de 1809. Johnston brosse un portrait détaillé de la topographie et de la géologie de la région, tout en insistant sur les paysages, les ressources minières, les cours d'eau et la flore locale. Il décrit aussi la qualité du sol, le climat, ainsi que les nombreuses plantes et racines utilisées par les autochtones à des fins médicinales. Il y est question de la capture d'un castor ayant deux queux et la découverte d'une tête humaine bien préservée. En se basant sur ses observations du pays, Johnston en vient à croire que les États-Unis occupent des terres sur lesquelles ils n'ont aucun droit, et que la Terre n'est pas aplatie aux pôles.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
