<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>Journal of the Second, Third and Fourth Expeditions to the Missouri, 1805, 1806 with the Supplement to the Second Expedition.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="McKenzie, Charles.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">McKenzie, Charles. Journal of the Second, Third and Fourth Expeditions to the Missouri, 1805, 1806 with the Supplement to the Second Expedition. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0010</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0010</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2355b</span></p>








<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>This document, a copy of account 2355b, regroups the travel journals of Charles Mackenzie in the Mississouri (sic) river region. Written between 1805 and 1806, these journals detail his second, third and fourth expeditions there, and provide extensive information on the lifestyles of the Mandan, Hidatsa, Crow, Snake, Enasas, Cheyenne, and Assiniboine peoples. The author explains how Native diplomacy in the fur trade includes feasts, harangues and ceremonies involving the smoking of peace pipes. He states that while some Natives are fearful of white men and do not desire them in their country, others like the Cheyenne wish to establish trading relationships with them. Mackenzie also describes mounted buffalo hunts and provides rich information on the ordeals and challenges which every fur trader and traveler must face in the region.</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Ce document, qui est une copie du texte 2355b, regroupe les journaux des deuxième, troisième et quatrième voyages de Charles Mackenzie dans la région de la rivière Mississouri (sic) en 1805 et 1806. Ces journaux fournissent de nombreux détails sur la vie des Mandans, Gros Ventres (Hidatsa), Corbeaux, Serpents, Enasas, Cheyennes et Assiniboines. L'auteur y explique en quoi la diplomatie autochtone et le commerce des fourrures sont accompagnés par des cérémonies, fêtes, harangues et échanges paisibles du calumet. Il raconte que certains Indiens craignent les blancs, alors que d'autres, tels que les Cheyennes, désirent établir des relations commerciales avec ceux-ci. Mackenzie décrit aussi la chasse montée au bison ainsi que les difficultés et défis qui guettent tout voyageur et traiteur dans la région.</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
