<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<html>

 <head>
  <title>The Mississouri Indians, 1809.  - Abstracts</title>
  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=iso-8859-1" />
<META Name="author" Content="McKenzie, Charles.">
  <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../../../../ss/css/FurTrade_StandAlonePage.IE.css" />
 </head><script TYPE="text/javascript" language="JavaScript">
<!-- hide
function Add(){
if(parent.BackLink==1)
{
parent.BackLink=" ";
return("<a href='javascript:document.rechBis.submit()' target=mainFrame>Back to search results</a> | ");
}
else
return("");
}
// end hiding -->
</script>
<script language="javascript">if(parent.main2)  parent.main2.cols='0%,100%';</script>

<body class="NotesAndAbstract">

<p class="NavBar"><script language="javascript">document.write(Add());</script><a href="../../../../search/searchfs.htm" target="mainFrame">New search</a> | <a href="Pg001.html">First Page</a> | <a href="notes.html">Notes</a> | Abstract</p>
<p class="EnTeteTranscription">McKenzie, Charles. The Mississouri Indians, 1809. An electronic transcription. MFTP #0009</p><p class="teiHeader-idno">McGill Fur Trade Project Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MFTP 0009</span></p>
<p class="teiHeader-idno">Masson Number: <span style="font-weight:bold;">MASS 2355a</span></p>








<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Abstract</p>
<p>Divided into several sections, this document by Charles Mackenzie, a North West Company clerk, describes an expedition he undertook with a group of voyageurs in the Mississouri (sic) region for the explicit purpose of expanding the commercial boundaries of the Montreal-based North West Company.  In a letter addressed to Roderick Mackenzie dated Spring 1809, Charles introduces his account of the Missouri River Natives by explaining the motives of his many voyages to the region. The account itself is composed of selected extracts from the journals he kept during his first expedition in 1804, second expedition in 1805, third expedition in the fall of 1805, and fourth expedition in June 1806. He describes with remarkable detail the lifestyles and customs of various Native groups, such as the Mandans and the Gros Ventres (Hidatsa).</p>
</div>

<div class="teiHeader-abstract"><p class="div-head">Résumé</p>
<p>Dans ce document subdivisé en plusieurs sections, Charles Mackenzie, un commis pour la Compagnie du Nord Ouest, raconte qu'il prit part à un voyage avec de nombreux engagés au pays du Mississouri (sic), repoussant ainsi les frontières de la compagnie. Dans une lettre datée du printemps 1809 et adressée à Roderick Mackenzie, Charles introduit son récit sur les Indiens de la rivière Missouri en expliquant les motifs qui l'ont poussé à explorer cette région à plusieurs reprises. Son récit est composé d'extraits choisis de son journal et inclut la première expédition de 1804, la seconde de 1805 (ainsi que son supplément), la troisième de l'automne 1805, et la quatrième de juin 1806. Il y décrit de façon détaillée les moeurs et coutumes des Indiens de la région, dont les Mandans et les Gros Ventres (Hidatsa).</p>
</div>

</body>

</html>
